Guide to the Mark Arthur May papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1911-1971; Series IV
  - The Institute of Human Relations
    - Institute of Human Relations at Yale, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 54)
    - Its Present Activities, undated (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - A Retrospective View of the Institute of Human Relations at Yale, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 56)
  - The Integration of Culture Through Personality, 1953, undated (Box 12, Folder 57)
  - The Integration of the Social Sciences, 1940, undated (Box 12, Folder 58)
  - Intelligence Tests in Schools, undated (Box 12, Folder 59)
  - An Interpretation of Pseudo-Conditioning, 1945-1953 (Box 13, Folder 60)
  - Introduction to Behavior Theory, undated (Box 13, Folder 61)
  - Is There a Normal Child?, undated (Box 13, Folder 62)
  - Is There a Science of Human Relations?, 1934-1935 (Box 13, Folder 63)
  - Is There Such a Thing as Character-Building?, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 64)
  - Jobless Youth Eager to Help World, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 65)
  - The Kulpe School in the Psychology of Thinking, undated (Box 13, Folder 66)
  - Limitations of Scientific Method in Respect to the Work of the Social Sciences, 1938, undated (Box 13, Folder 67)
  - Measurements of Personality [radio talk], undated (Box 13, Folder 68)
  - Measures of Social Prestige, 1940, undated (Box 13, Folder 69)
  - Measuring Achievement in College Subjects, undated (Box 13, Folder 70)
  - The Method of Measurements by RelativePosition as Applied to Religious Efficiency, undated (Box 13, Folder 71)
  - Motion Pictures, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 72)
  - Motion Pictures in Education, 1946, undated (Box 13, Folder 73)
  - The Nature of Learning, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 74)
  - A New Deal in Education, undated (Box 13, Folder 75)
  - New Duties for Schools and Parents, 1934, undated (Box 13, Folder 76)
  - Occupational Opportunities in and Qualifications for Research Work, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 77)
  - Our Families in Wartime (Morale on the Home Front), 1942 undated (Box 13, Folder 78)
  - Our Indebtedness to Sidney Lanier, undated (Box 13, Folder 79)
  - Overt/Covert Responses, undated (Box 13, Folder 80)
  - Paradoxes in Education, undated (Box 13, Folder 81)
  - Personality Experimentally Approached, 1933 undated (Box 13, Folder 82)
  - The Place of Motion Pictures in Adult Education, [abstract], undated (Box 13, Folder 83)
  - Popular Misconceptions of Psychology, undated (Box 13, Folder 84)
  - Predicting Academic Success, undated (Box 13, Folder 85)
  - Problems in International Communication, undated (Box 13, Folder 86)
  - Problems of Individuals and Societies Today and Tomorrow, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 87)
  - Propaganda for Freedom, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 88)
  - The Psychological Conditions of Peace
    - 1943 [abstract] (Box 14, Folder 89)
    - n.d. (Box 14, Folder 90)
  - The Psychological Foundations of Peace, 1944, undated (Box 14, Folder 91)
  - Psychological Methods in the Study of Personality with Special Reference to the Study of Criminals, undated (Box 14, Folder 92)
  - Psychology and the Principles of Human Relations, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 93)
  - The Psychology of Deceit, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 94)
  - The Psychology of Learning from Demonstration Films, 1945-1953, undated (Box 14, Folder 95)
  - The Psychology of Reading, undated (Box 14, Folder 96)
  - Race Relations and Culture Conflicts, undated (Box 14, Folder 97)
  - Recent Improvements in Devices for Rating Character, [with Hugh Hartshorne], 1940 undated (Box 14, Folder 98)
  - Recent Research in the Problems of Youth, undated (Box 14, Folder 99)
  - Re-education for National Defense [speech outline], 1942 (Box 14, Folder 100)
  - The Relation Between Fear and Frustration, undated (Box 14, Folder 101)
  - The Relation of Psychiatry to Education, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 102)
  - Research and the Ph.D. in the Department of Education, 1940, undated (Box 14, Folder 103)
  - Resources and the Education of the Individual, 1940, undated (Box 14, Folder 104)
  - The Role of Conscience in Character and Personality, undated (Box 14, Folder 105)
  - The Role of Psychology in Education, undated (Box 14, Folder 106)
  - Science and Morality, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 107)
  - Scientific Approaches to the Problems of Social Work, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 108)
  - The Social Stimulus Conceptions of Personality: A Reply to Criticisms, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 109)
  - Some Limitations of the Social Sciences, undated (Box 14, Folder 110)
  - Some Queries about the Concept of Equality, undated (Box 14, Folder 111)
  - Statistical Methods in Personality Studies, undated (Box 14, Folder 112)
  - Study and Learning [4 chapters], undated (Box 14, Folder 113)
  - Summary of Research Findings on the Influence of Motion Pictures on Attitudes, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 114)
  - The Teacher as a Transmitter of Culture, 1940, 1950, undated (Box 14, Folder 115)
  - Ten Tests of Measurement, 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 116)
  - Theological Education, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 117)
  - Thorndike, Edward Lee, 1949-1950 (Box 14, Folder 118)
  - Tomorrow's Citizens, undated (Box 14, Folder 119)
  - Toward a Science of Education, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 120)
  - Transfer of Trainingfrom Physical Education to Effective Social Participation [outline], 1942 (Box 15, Folder 121)
  - Twentieth Century Life Patterns, 1939, undated (Box 15, Folder 122)
  - United States Foreign Policy, 1956-1957 (Box 15, Folder 123)
  - The United States Information Service, undated (Box 15, Folder 124)
  - Dseof a Motivational Film for the Development of Interest in Reading, [with N. L. Jenkinson], undated (Box 15, Folder 125)
  - The Voice of America, 1958, undated (Box 15, Folder 126)
  - What is Character Education?, 1936-1937, undated (Box 15, Folder 127)
  - Which is it: Religion vs. Science or Religion vs. Religion?, undated (Box 15, Folder 128)
  - What Science offers on Character Education, 1928, undated (Box 15, Folder 129)
  - What Should the New Administration do about Psychological Warfare?, undated (Box 15, Folder 130)
  - Book reviews, 1927-1970 (Box 15, Folder 131)
- Photographs, undated; Series V
  This series is comprised of two sections: Persons and Subjects. Each is alphabetically arranged. Most of the photographs are not of May himself but they all relate to organizations and peers in his professional life. Some photographs are of significant figures in psychology at mid-century. Two interesting photographs are of May with members of the President's Advisory Commission to the United States Information Agency on which he served.
  - Persons
    - Child, Irvin, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Dollard, John [recording a psychoanalytic interview], undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Ford, Clellan S., undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Hovland, Carl I., undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Hull, Clark L., undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - May, Mark A.
      - WIth George Peter Murdock, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - With members of the United States Information Agency Advisory Commission, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified persons, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Subjects
    - Experiments with rats, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Institute of Human Relations entrance, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)